hey everyone welcome back to our Channel
I am back with another interesting topic
in the tosa automation
playlist so continuing with our topic on
test automation obstacles let's look at
our next obstacle which is called the
obvious now this is one of the easy
obstacles but the reason I'm showing you
this obstacle
is it's a pretty common scenario which
you will encounter in your applications
so it's quite useful to know how to get
around this uh obstacle pretty easily
right so in this particular obstacle we
need to generate a random string by
clicking on the button so once we click
on the button it is going to generate a
random string and then there is a
dropdown okay and this drop- down
contains one of these random strings
okay so you don't know which random text
will be generated but uh it is part of
this particular list now you need to uh
select a particular item from this list
which matches that random text okay so
in this case uh it starts with KY so if
I select this and then I click on submit
then the obstacle is completed okay so
we have to automate this particular
scenario using
tosa so let's go to tosa and let's
quickly see how we can automate this
particular obstacle so first first of
all uh let me quickly go ahead and
create a module for this particular
obstacle so I'm going to scan this
application and we need couple of
elements right here so we need the
Generate random text then we need the
text box and then uh we also need the
select item box right so this is a
select uh element which contains a lot
of different elements right so these are
the three uh Elements which we require
and then we also require the submit
button okay so actually four elements
now let's go ahead and rename our module
so to to match this particular obstacle
ID and we are going to save this and uh
we will close
this okay so the next part is to add a
test case so we are going here and and
we are going to add a test case
here okay and then let's add the
particular module here with which we'll
work with and now let's go ahead and
look at the test steps
right so the first test step is to click
on this particular button so I will use
uh X here to click on it
and then uh it will generate a random
text right now the next step is to store
the random text into a buffer variable
and for that we can use the action mode
buffer so uh let's add another step into
the test case okay and here we are going
to use the buffer action mode I'm going
to remove this particular module
attribute because we have already uh
clicked on this okay so we are going to
now use the
buffer action mode here and we are going
to specify a buffer name let's call it
R&D okay and then the next step is to uh
select that particular uh randomly
generated text in the select drop down
okay so again uh we need this step where
we will do this okay and we make sure
that uh we remove any any other steps
which have been uh included here or any
other values okay and then in the select
link we are just going to specify the
buffer here okay so this is the buffer
value which will be selected and then
the final step is to click on the submit
link
okay so here we are again going to use
the X to click on this so these are all
the four steps okay so you need to use
the module four times because we have
got four different steps here and is
always recommended to have just one
action uh or one value selected in one
of your modules right so uh you can
always go ahead and rename all the steps
so here it is to click on
random uh
button okay and then here uh we we
are buffer random
text and then here uh we
select
random
text and finally we click on
submit
okay so now our test case is complete we
will mark it as completed and uh now we
will go ahead and try to run this in
scratchbook okay so as you can see uh it
clicked on the Generate random text it
buffered uh the randomly generated text
and then uh it used that buffer value to
select it from the drop down and then it
clicked on the submit okay it's a pretty
simple obstacle as I mentioned earlier
but it's a pretty common scenario which
you will come across numerous times in
your
application so you should be comfortable
uh with uh how to automate this
particular scenario uh in your
application using
tosa that's all for this particular
video if you have any questions then
please leave it in the comments if you
like this video then please subscribe to
our Channel thanks for watching and I
will see you in the next
video